<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: isolinux | Gittu's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/tags/isolinux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-18T03:51:56+06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.sarim.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sarim Khan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[sarim2005@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make persistent ubuntu live virtualbox image]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/2013/12/18/how-to-make-persistent-ubuntu-live-virtualbox-image/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T02:44:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.sarim.me/2013/12/18/how-to-make-persistent-ubuntu-live-virtualbox-image</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK, i&#39;ve read the title, wtf is that ? So first i&#39;m going to explain what i&#39;m going to do, and why i&#39;m doing it. When we want to try ubuntu without installing, we have two option,</p>

<ol>
<li>Throw the iso into virtualbox and taste the new system.</li>
<li>Make a live usb disk and boot my computer from it.</li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p>Now i want to persist some changes, i installed some packages, created some files, i want to have them when i boot this live system again. Easy, just add some persistent space when creating the live usb. But if i want to do that in virtualbox ? What if i dont want to reboot my pc, i want do my other tasks and want to try out ubuntu in parallel ? Voila! install that ubuntu inside virtualbox. OK, but now i dont want to waste a few gigs of my disk space (not to mention the time to install ubuntu). I want to use persistance with that live system. There was no way till now :( </p>

<p>But fear not, Thats what i&#39;m going to do now :D I&#39;m gonna make a virtualbox image from ubuntu iso, adding a persistent space with it in the process.</p>

<h1>Requirement</h1>

<ol>
<li>Virtualbox.</li>
<li>Unetbootin.</li>
</ol>

<h1>Procedure</h1>

<p>I did this in mac, but pretty same process will be applicable for linux too (hopefully). Now head over to terminal and follow the steps.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Lets create a folder and do all the bullshitting inside it.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ mkdir ubuntulive
$ cd ubuntulive
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>Lets make a empty 1.0GB image to hold all that bullshit.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ dd if=/dev/zero of=ubuntu.img bs=1m count=1024
$ ls -lsh
total 2097152
2097152 -rw-r--r--  1 sarim  staff   1.0G Dec 18 02:42 ubuntu.img
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>Bullshit container creation done, now register this bullshit as disk in the system.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ open -a Disk\ Utility ubuntu.img
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>In Disk Utility, right click on the <code>ubuntu.img</code> in the left side pane. Select <code>Open Disk Image</code> from popup menu. It&#39;ll show a error msg.</p></li>
<li><p>Now check the disk listing, you&#39;ll see a new disk added at the end. It is <code>/dev/disk6</code> for me.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ diskutil list

/dev/disk6
   #:                       TYPE NAME                    SIZE       IDENTIFIER
   0:                                                   *1.1 GB     disk6
</code></pre></div>
<p>Yay ! our bullshit disk is registered in the system :D</p></li>
<li><p>Now lets partition the disk. We are going to create a <code>fat32</code> partition named <code>UBUNTULIVE</code>.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ diskutil partitionDisk /dev/disk6 1 MBRFormat fat32 UBUNTULIVE 100%
Started partitioning on disk6
Unmounting disk
Creating the partition map
Waiting for the disks to reappear
Formatting disk6s1 as MS-DOS (FAT32) with name UBUNTULIVE
512 bytes per physical sector
/dev/rdisk6s1: 2093024 sectors in 261628 FAT32 clusters (4096 bytes/cluster)
bps=512 spc=8 res=32 nft=2 mid=0xf8 spt=32 hds=128 hid=2 drv=0x80 bsec=2097150 bspf=2044 rdcl=2 infs=1 bkbs=6
Mounting disk
Finished partitioning on disk6
/dev/disk6
   #:                       TYPE NAME                    SIZE       IDENTIFIER
   0:     FDisk_partition_scheme                        *1.1 GB     disk6
   1:                 DOS_FAT_32 UBUNTULIVE              1.1 GB     disk6s1
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>Now the <code>UBUNTULIVE</code> drive will be mounted in finder. Open <code>Unetbootin</code>. Select the iso, enter some how much space you want for persistance. Select <code>/dev/disk6s1</code> in <code>Drive</code>. Click OK and Let it finish making the live disk. It happens in a snap in my ssd powered system, your experience may vary.</p>

<p><img src="http://cl.ly/T0hy/Screen%20Shot%202013-12-18%20at%202.48.37%20AM.jpg" alt="Unetbootin"></p></li>
<li><p>After unetbootin is finished, Go to <code>UBUNTULIVE</code> drive. Inside the drive, open <code>syslinux.cfg</code> in a text editor. (I used Textmate). Add the following lines at the end.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">label ubnentry6
menu label ^Try Ubuntu without installing in Gittu way
kernel /casper/vmlinuz
append initrd=/casper/initrd.lz live-media=/dev/sda1 live-media-path=/casper/ file=/cdrom/preseed/ubuntu.seed ignore_uuid boot=casper quiet splash -- persistent
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>Save the file and unmount/eject the <code>UBUNTULIVE</code> drive.</p></li>
<li><p>GUI time is over, back to terminal. Now our image is ready. Convert it for virtualbox.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="text">$ VBoxManage convertfromraw -format VDI ubuntu.img ubuntu_vbox.vdi
Converting from raw image file=&quot;ubuntu.img&quot; to file=&quot;ubuntu_vbox.vdi&quot;...
Creating dynamic image with size 1073741824 bytes (1024MB)...
</code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>Phew! Done :D Now open virtualbox. Create a new vm/Edit Existing, in storage section, select <code>Choose Existing Disk</code> and select this <code>ubuntu_vbox.vdi</code> there. Boot the vm, in unetbootin menu, select the last option and press enter to boot.</p>

<p><img src="http://cl.ly/T0RH/Screen%20Shot%202013-12-18%20at%202.51.41%20AM.jpg" alt="image"></p></li>
</ol>

<h3>Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>For linux, step 3 to 6 can be done using gparted. <code>$ gparted ./ubuntu.img</code> will do.</li>
<li>This guide is based on ubuntu 13.10. A new boot flag <code>live-media</code> is needed for 13.10. That was taked from <a href="http://schmidi2.wordpress.com/2013/11/19/error-reading-libudevhwdb-bin-no-such-file-or-directory/">schmidi2.wordpress.com</a>. If you are using another version, you may ommit the flag in step 8.</li>
</ul>

<p>Now, this thing still wasted 2gigs of disk space, didn&#39;t it ? So whats the point ? There is none :v you may take it as bullshitting, or a scienctific experiment for educational purposes, your wish. Good luck and Happy linuxing (y)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
