<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tags: javascript | Gittu's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/tags/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-06T02:29:58+06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.sarim.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sarim Khan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[sarim2005@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using twitter's embedded timeline as data source]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.sarim.me/2013/09/06/using-twitters-embedded-timeline-as-data-source/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-06T00:15:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.sarim.me/2013/09/06/using-twitters-embedded-timeline-as-data-source</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The title is kinda ambiguous, i know. We all know that twitter has introduced api 1.1 and removed api 1.0. Now in 1.0 we could get any public user&#39;r timeline without auth. So we could just get users timeline as jsonp and create a twitter widget like &quot;Recent Tweets&quot; without any server side code. But…… those good old days are gone. Now you need a twitter client and need to make oauth-authorized request to get that data. And obviously that rules out the client side implementation as no one would publish his token,secret,key etc.. in a public accessible javascript file.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Now twitter provides a widget with limited customizing functionality to embed one&#39;s tweets. But you can&#39;t use your own design with that, you are stuck with two &quot;light&quot; and &quot;dark&quot; theme twitter is so kind to provide.</p>

<p>Today i came up with a hack around this widget, you still need to create a widget from twitter, but you can create your own widget with it. How ?</p>

<p>Check the <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/sarim/S7AeM/embedded/result/">DEMO</a>  first.</p>

<p>Now check the sources, things are pretty self-explanatory. The twitter widget creates a iframe. Interesting thing is, instead of just loading the iframe from twitter, it creates a empty iframe, then writes the html inside the iframe. The src attr of iframe remains empty, that enables us to access it freely. Thats what i did, i let it load, made it invisible by sending it off the page using css. Now i just parsed the tweets from the iframe and created my own widget.</p>

<p>You can also see it in my site&#39;s sidebar.</p>

<p>Let me know your ideas about this in the comments section below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
